<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Reconstructing Christmas]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Reconstructing Christmas]]></description>
        <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:16:24 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://reconstructingchristmas.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 10]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 10</h1>,<p>“Do Christmas”</p>,<p>This phrase gets me. “When are we going to do Christmas?”</p>,<p>We use it for talking about family gatherings, and specifically for “opening presents.”</p>,<p>As children, this is certainly the pinnacle. As children.</p>,<p>And to be fair, we do have a lot of children in our families. But it still feels…over-emphasized.</p>,<p>As I think about what we do on Christmas Day, our tradition is usually:</p>,<ol><li>Wake up tired because we were wrapping presents until late at night</li><li>Children open their stockings (orange, peppermint stick, small toy)</li><li>Get up and make breakfast - maybe a coffee cake - and beat off children’s repeated requests to open presents.</li><li>Eat breakfast, antsilly.</li><li>Move to the living room.</li><li>Look for the Christmas story in the bible.</li><li>Heather has the kids act it out as I read it.</li><li>Avoid the flurry of ripping by insisting that only one present gets opened at a time, with a tiny break between each so we can appreciate the gift.</li><li>Clean up.</li><li>Fight over toys, argue with each other, and do whatever we want the rest of the day, as long as it’s inclusive of the whole 0-12 age range of the kids.</li></ol>,<p>Ew.</p>,<p>I wonder if there’s even a “service order” for the Christ-Mass? I really, really want something more holy than our tradition includes.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiLRVlrTDW603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qWJ3YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fK2JOwpo7bJg_eU7yuCv5aRxXqYAdap-3oNFnvUrMQuGBsJn4iIU4qiI7rtkNRCyN3QM9H6MERbs5vardVPaSYfSw_S0bbVqT_MZvzi0mZKhMBaAxuwsxEOoAimHHMUHJDWsM9a64wiUFzmeyJBnwqCu2dA02yVRoa7w_SARXgvt5fCzQH2eHdd9v0x3p1f4KAbKU-PcqHZCLj7eWgAittvQFpHUKgDbQ-QDq7y8roNzVej9M-C5Fcc0n4ddPLO2SdJMvKqphTi6JqClYfFeIlW-37SzaxMIpUvg_Q1vFkgPcPwA6Qwsg5u53eB4vUK5Q8UxjQ0DcQ8tVyHnVjP3gkpl3djvUHzDiXdw" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiLRVlrTDW603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qWJ3YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fK2JOwpo7bJg_eU7yuCv5aRxXqYAdap-3oNFnvUrMQuGBsJn4iIU4qiI7rtkNRCyN3QM9H6MERbs5vardVPaSYfSw_S0bbVqT_MZvzi0mZKhMBaAxuwsxEOoAimHHMUHJDWsM9a64wiUFzmeyJBnwqCu2dA02yVRoa7w_SARXgvt5fCzQH2eHdd9v0x3p1f4KAbKU-PcqHZCLj7eWgAittvQFpHUKgDbQ-QDq7y8roNzVej9M-C5Fcc0n4ddPLO2SdJMvKqphTi6JqClYfFeIlW-37SzaxMIpUvg_Q1vFkgPcPwA6Qwsg5u53eB4vUK5Q8UxjQ0DcQ8tVyHnVjP3gkpl3djvUHzDiXdw</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">5c2cefc3-0d77-4340-b7ef-36d6666613cb</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 13:16:22 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 9]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 9</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/4282611a-9729-450a-87d7-4ad415c73460.jpg">,<p>ChristmasEvangelism<em>!</em></p>,<p>I made a derogatory statement about a “sinner” the other day to one of my friends. He responded with something like “why would you hold her to your standards or convictions? She’s not even a Christian.”</p>,<p>He was right. This celebrity is not a follower of Christ, as far as I know. Why should I expect her to live like I believe?</p>,<p>And I’m all game to tell Christians “Remember, Jesus is the reason for the season.” In fact, my mind drifts back to a <a href="https://youtu.be/3EAvzhPlYWM" title="">cantata</a> my parent’s sang in. My Dad had a tenor solo in it. I can still remember his delight in doing the octave slide at the end of it.</p>,<p>So why are we compelled to hold non followers of Christ to the true meaning of Christmas?</p>,<p>Is it the same feeling I get holding “the world” to the traditional biblical model of marriage? Like you can do whatever you want do, just don’t call it marriage? Celebrate this season however you want, just don’t call it Christmas? So maybe, “happy holidays” is actually better?</p>,<p>I‘m really not looking for a fight, I’m just trying to figure out why we feel compelled to “fix people’s perspectives about the TRUE meaning of Christmas.”</p>,<p>As I think about this though, there’s a bit too much parallel for comfort here. In the same way that there is often too little distinction between a Christian marriage, and a non-Christian one (or Christian or non-Christian “committed homosexual relationship”), how differently do Christian households celebrate Advent and the “Christmas season” than the unbelieving world around us?</p>,<p>Can we name 10 things that we do differently? How about 5?</p>,<p>And I feel like we have to go beyond just saying “well, we’re different because we know the true meaning behind it.” That feels weak. If the practices are the same, just the heart is different, that leaves me wanting more.</p>,<p>I want a marked difference between the folks that just “do Christmas” and those who follow Jesus and celebrate the birth.</p>,<p>I no longer think that I need to “hold them to our beliefs” when it comes to ChristmasEvangelism. Absolutely we must have a reason for the hope that we have and know winsome ways of talking about its meaning. But the hard sell, the condescending tone, let’s stop it, I’d say.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBidou8MkDlx2AU4IoTRxt3RrUtlpxYT4d9ytk7jF8fN7fs-lsaOwplo0dYbeh8W6zPlrHZWk0fZhnTSD08F6l5iloCVjU_ETCTEqFC3XTUuiEkbuIDwfoQMXaHN6U7ut6iCh9OPus2C0bUTyH7M5vZiEqVKBEAZ0E2Ym0ggqwIxjhoIb0hruWXOBSULNZbwPoaenPNfeOdBBNkpD7f1BOgg5uK_315zMQbZ0893U3bFa3Y6AxFaq8UHexxMZby97hay09QakdQQYNtB4hGR2lxbRb2K8HqZ9liK-5BLz66qXtcQ6cZoWZT6nFkXlFKw-KqJzttp352wWwqigsj1CUy0mA7w_AjuggAPn7HZ6j5ZCp0jyTG5AQ1cDZo_zpBu63lNg1tX1Vn85J5dP" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-9/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">b7877258-d703-49c3-af8c-90c3da323154</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2018 12:57:40 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 7]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 7</h1>,<p>The decorations.</p>,<p>It’s possible that I’ll be braving the cold this afternoon to hang up a 9-foot Christmas tree lighted display on the side of the house that I built last December. We already dressed the windows, put up and decorated the tree, and added an advent candle wreath to the dining room table.</p>,<p>Green. Red. Gold. Purple? These are our pallets.</p>,<p>I actually love little lights. They sparkle. They lend a soft light to everything. They feel like hope to me.</p>,<p>And the nativity scenes. I like those too. Especially fond of the ones where you don’t put the baby Jesus in the manger until Christmas morning.</p>,<p>Why do I feel such joy at seeing houses decorated with lights? I do.</p>,<p>But not so much the big inflatable crap. Just stop. Please.</p>,<p>And mistletoe. I don’t know that I’ve seen it before, but it’s in the songs.</p>,<p>And what’s up with evergreen? We put it EVERYWHERE. On the mantle, around the bannisters, over the door frames, in the centerpiece… I mean, evergreens are my favorite trees, cypresses especially. But where did that come from and what does it mean?</p>,<p>Ornaments. Those colorful balls are cool. And for the first few years of our marriage, my mother in law would make ones for each of the kids, with a bunch of little pics of them on the backs. Heavy, but so fun.</p>,<p>—</p>,<p>I’m not really processing much, more like capturing the things I’m thinking about when thinking about Christmas decorations. The one thing that interests me about what I’ve said is how much I like lights. And there’s an obvious correlation there, with Jesus being the light of the world, coming as the light in the darkness, the natural light in these early dark evenings, etc.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBgck2u4wiQOXXYATQihN3C3dmlR2WjEh_h136yRucfz8nt9zaeworKkWTZ2h92GxLnP-WkclabR9WCfN4HSw3iVmKWjJ2FT8REKMCkXLddOSqISROwjPR-jABdqc3tRuqzpIKP24-ywYbRuR_MdsTi8mYapUIIQB3YSZiTSCCjDjmKHghrSGe9ZcYJJQcxnvQ-jpKc-1dw50kI3SUHt_kA5CDu7r_TUnc5At3Xw3dXesVrcjILGVanyQ9_FExtvLXiErbb0BaR0Bhg00HiGZ3aVF9JsYr4dpn6WIL7nE_LrqZS2xTpymRZnPqUVROQWrj4ronK323TmbhTAqqGyP0FSLyQDvj8AOKODAObud3qOl0CmSPJMb0NDVgNnjPOmGrvcUmHV1vdUfOPGXTQ" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBgck2u4wiQOXXYATQihN3C3dmlR2WjEh_h136yRucfz8nt9zaeworKkWTZ2h92GxLnP-WkclabR9WCfN4HSw3iVmKWjJ2FT8REKMCkXLddOSqISROwjPR-jABdqc3tRuqzpIKP24-ywYbRuR_MdsTi8mYapUIIQB3YSZiTSCCjDjmKHghrSGe9ZcYJJQcxnvQ-jpKc-1dw50kI3SUHt_kA5CDu7r_TUnc5At3Xw3dXesVrcjILGVanyQ9_FExtvLXiErbb0BaR0Bhg00HiGZ3aVF9JsYr4dpn6WIL7nE_LrqZS2xTpymRZnPqUVROQWrj4ronK323TmbhTAqqGyP0FSLyQDvj8AOKODAObud3qOl0CmSPJMb0NDVgNnjPOmGrvcUmHV1vdUfOPGXTQ</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">188e60d7-95f7-4039-8fb3-5d6a606fdc22</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2018 21:13:30 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 6]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 6</h1>,<p>A very special Christmas…the one-upsmanship that crushingly oppresses</p>,<blockquote>And this Christmas, will be 
A very special Christmas, for me</blockquote>,<p>Maybe you know the <a href="https://youtu.be/pj1mVUEHeUE" title="">Donny Hathaway song</a> I learned last Christmas. It rolls round and round in my head, carving the expectation: the best of all Christmases will be this Christmas!</p>,<p>What if it’s not?</p>,<p>Have a holly, jolly Christmas, it's the best time of the year</p>,<p>It's the most wonderful time of the year</p>,<p>It's the hap-happiest season of all</p>,<p>Simply having a wonderful Christmas time</p>,<p>Have yourself a merry little Christmas, let your heart be light</p>,<p>Now I know those are not the Christmas hymns that know as beloved carols, but they are what we hear everywhere we go. And they get stuck in your head.</p>,<p>But beyond the songs, the movies, your childhood, and every single commercial, I’m expected to have the best, the most fun, the most meaningful, the wonderfullest Christmas EVER! Every year. That pressure is for the birds. No thank you!</p>,<p>Now as an Enneagram 7, I’m always anticipating the next great thing. Ever searching for what my last search only temporarily satisfied. And I’ll own that dysfunction.</p>,<p>But what if I looked forward to this Christmas, not with this air of an unsustainable month-long magical Christmas season, but as a season of Advent, of anticipating the celebration of an arrival? And expected the day itself to be holy yet ordinary, special yet simple, shared and present?</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/75792efe-5418-4b1a-bda8-2147c8aecd0e.jpg">,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBhIH2u4wiQOXXYATQihN3C3dmlR2WjEh_h136yRucfz8nt9zaeworKkWTZ2h92GxLnP-WkclabR9WCfN4HSw3iVmKWjJ2FT8REKMCkXLddOSqISROwjPR-jABdqc3tRuqzpIKP24-ywYbRuR_MdsTi8mYapUIIQB3YSZiTSCCjDjmKHghrSGe9ZcYJJQcxnvQ-jpKc-1dw50kI3SUHt_kA5CDu7r_TUnc5At3Xw3dXesVrcjILGVanyQ9_FExtvLXiErbb0BaR0Bhg00HiGZ3aVF9JsYr4dpn6WIL7nE_LrqZS2xTpymRZnPqUVROQWrj4ronK323TmbhTAqqGyP0FSLyQDvj8AOKODAObud3qOl0CmSPJMb0NDVgNnjPOmGrvcUmHV1vdUfONaXTA" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-6/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">92565be1-7f1e-4d18-be81-6728fb056c5a</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Dec 2018 21:08:46 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 5]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 5</h1>,<p>“Merry Christmas.”</p>,<p>The practice of greeting someone with Merry Christmas feels nostalgically 1920’s. There’s such warmth to it. It’s just cheery.</p>,<p>But in post-I-don’t-want-to-say-Obama-but-Obama-US, I feel this silent cheer from many Christians when someone says Merry Christmas instead of Happy Holidays. And sometimes someone starts with Happy Holidays, and when the other person says Merry Christmas, they act “freed” and respond again with a head-cocked, glistened-eye “yes, Merry Christmas.”</p>,<p><em>And I feel the pressure to respond that way. Like it’s my Christian duty, like I’m letting down the church if I don’t, like I’m missing an opportunity to witness if I don’t.</em></p>,<p>Sheesh, that’s some pressure!</p>,<p>Part of it is that I don’t like to follow rules. I also bristle strongly at “having to” say “the Lord is risen indeed” on Easter when someone says “The Lord is risen.”</p>,<p>Now, of course, I could shut up, go with the flow, hear the intended heart behind the greeting or farewell and just say Merry Christmas (which I do), but I die a little when I do that.</p>,<p>Why?</p>,<p>Is it that I feel that the person saying it doesn’t really experience the core, Emmanuel God with us? And it cheapens it?</p>,<p>Is it that I don’t believe they are actually merry and that their Christmas gatherings and day are shallow and fraught with artificial relationships and gluttony? (boy, that was honestly dark)</p>,<p>Is it that <em>I</em> am not experiencing the merriness of Christmas and am jealous of those who seem to have a storybook experience?</p>,<p>Maybe that’s the most honest one. Like when someone says Merry Christmas, I’d like to say back “not really…‘disappointing Christmas’ is more accurate.” So it that it? I’m disappointed and so I don’t want people ruining my pity party?</p>,<p>But I’m not a scrooge. I want to have a really wonderful time. Part of why I don’t is that we don’t eat the things that we used to. We deal with some severe allergies in our family, so everything is modified or avoided altogether.</p>,<p>Oh, so food is tied to happiness, merriness, celebration. Not to be too hard on myself, but man.</p>,<p>So my prayer in this day is <strong>to be satisfied and filled with joy firstly and mostly by Himself</strong>. Otherwise it’s like I’m complaining to everyone at a wedding because I don’t like the music or the food.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/28993f34-63d9-4f20-9ab8-b7f7ebea9da6.png">,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBuJC2x0mceCyC3BCCKWJu6Vbk8pOKybEv-NuncQtjp_f83sujR2FNdWiqTP0PizWZc5f66gkjbYP66QZnA7Wu8QsBS0Zm4qfSIhRoWi5bloSlTByB-H5CB24QJvTm9ptVQcJpR93nwWjbSOS_5jN6cUkTJUKhDCgmzAzkUZQAWYcMxTckNZwz5oLTBJqLuN9CD095bn2zoEOslEaau8P0kHIwX29v-ZkDrKlm--m7o7V6nYEJLZSjQ_yPp7IeHvZK2SlrTcgrSPAsIHGIySzu7SIfhPj9TDtsxTxJZeYX1e9rCXWidO0KPM5tSgqp2D1URGds9W-O2ezEEYFle0RmmoxGeD9EdgBBRw4Z7fTe7QUOkWSZ3IDGroaMHucJ93Q9Z4Cs66ut_oDOLuXSw" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-5/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">04028ca0-1553-45e8-9972-050b25c83742</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 17:34:44 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 4]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 4</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/88d91840-4592-4834-985f-184cb9278964.jpg">,<p>There’s no other element of Christmas more quintessential than its MUSIC.</p>,<p>And this Amy Grant album is it for me. Always has been. Now it came out at the same time my family moved from Costa Rica to the scary world of the States. We crash landed in New Jersey for six terrible months, before gliding into a great 14 year season in San Antonio, Texas.</p>,<p>And this music was the soundtrack.</p>,<p>Ah a soundtrack for a season. Like a movie, the music of Christmas unifies and divides us. Well, that’s probably only true if you’re a worship leader. Then you hear ALL people’s expectations as they thrust upon you the songs you must include to avoid ruining their Christmas.</p>,<p>I hate that pressure.</p>,<p>But it’s undeniable. The season has a soundtrack.</p>,<p>There’s a lot of good music.</p>,<p>And there’s a lot of music.</p>,<p>In fact, though I’m listening to the aforementioned Christmas album as I type this in MOD Pizza, I’m being much more guarded this year about what I listen to. Because I feel like I’ve missed so much of what we are to celebrate, that I want to avoid being swept into it.</p>,<p>I’m not one to censor things, but I’m just trying to capture the HOLY essence, and that means blocking everything else out.</p>,<p>The idea of fuzzy antlers on Rudolph’s head, snowball fights, pumpkin pie shared by family, a star atop the Christmas tree, Santa’s sleigh, all the lore…I just need it to stop for a bit so I can focus!</p>,<p>So for this year, I’m trying to be vigilant. And I want to listen to the songs through a biblical narrative. Where is the story of Jesus? Where is the Anticipation of His arrival, not of Christmas morning!</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTBpxou8MkDlx2AU4IoTRxt3RrUtlpxYT4d9ytk7jF8fN7fs-lsaOwplo0dYbeh8W6zPlrHZWk0fZhnTSD08F6l5iloCVjU_ETCTEqFC3XTUuiEkbuIDwfoQMXaHN6U7ut6iCh9OPus2C0bUTyH7M5vZiEqVKBEAZ0E2Ym0ggqwIxjhoIb0hruWXOBSULNZbwPoaenPNfeOdBBNkpD7f1BOgg5uK_315zMQbZ0893U3bFa3Y6AxFaq8UHexxMZby97hay09QakdQQYNtB4hGR2lxbRb2K8HqZ9liK-5BLz66qXtcQ6cZoWZT6nFkXlFKw-KqJzttp352wWwqigsj1CUy0mA7w_AjuggAPn7HZ6j5ZCp0jyTG5AQ1cDZo_zpBu63lNg1tX1Vn84oJdK" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-4/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7f7e6aec-60a8-4c04-a337-77ee05f8e84a</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 19:05:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 3]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 3</h1>,<p>Christmas Morning!</p>,<p>Sure, it was staged…in classic Dad format - timer on the camera.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/068cb7a3-6318-4eb6-8543-3e488628f49e.jpg">,<p>I think that the way we “do” Christmas Morning is…off.</p>,<blockquote>Hurry now, wake up your eyes. Time for little ones to see, Daddy&rsquo;s got a big surprise hiding underneath the Christmas tree.</blockquote>,<p>If we have to “reinterpret” a moment or a tradition so that it has meaning, is that something we want to keep?</p>,<p>So the kids get up first because, well duh. Then they attack their stockings, which for our family is a piece of fruit, some small gifts, maybe some gum.</p>,<p>Then the asking begins. “Can we open presents yet?!?”</p>,<p>I remember that. I want to open presents too! But wait…first we have to read the Christmas story so that our paper-tearing frenzy has some MEANING.</p>,<p>Ew.</p>,<p>I don’t think I’m just dealing with “life with small children.” As parents, we are the leaders here. We can create whatever culture we feel is best. Doesn’t matter if the culture around us is different.</p>,<p>The tradition/rhythm/expectation/culture we create must be compelling, worship-inspiring, family-strengthening.</p>,<p>But first, why the feasting - food and gifts. Why is that what is expected? Because Jesus’ gift is so lavish that we have to respond in kind?</p>,<p>I feel like I’m honestly doing a pretty terrible job of deconstruction. But it’s only day three.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTxm603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qey0YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fS2FFYUy2aOkPvw2JT5vy1iUrSaPuwSZrB6WC9S8xS0JKxqfiJhBgVipbrpiVRCSP3EJ5P0IELtD2_qf1OdZBQ-vHwWTDaNiL5j9meX0zCVKlACAO6CTMTaQQVYMYxQ8ENaQ33rLnCJKHmMj6E0NNTnmvvHOggG6Wh9v4oHYQc3Nf7a07mKFu6-27q7lSt7kdAYivVuJaP8UTG28teISvtvAFpHQGGLTQeIZndpUX0mxivh2mfpYivucT8uullLbFOnKZFmc-pRVE5BatPiuiSrfbdJZuFMCqo7IDQVIvJAO-PwA4o4MA5u70-oKXQKZI8kxvQ0NWA2XqedEPXewrMurrd6g84hZdJ" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-3/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2b7593f9-420b-4c35-a9ed-b18c70808191</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 18:11:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 2]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 2</h1>,<h2>Wish Lists.</h2>,<p>We do this you know. We make and receive wish lists. For gifts.</p>,<p>I can’t help but wish that I’d know people well enough to not have to ask for their wish list. And I get it. Decades of jokes come from re-gifting things and there’s a whole demographic of people that seems to have a disproportionately low success rate in finding gifts that “stick.”</p>,<p>What if I didn’t buy anything for anybody that I didn’t know so well, I could just pick something because he/she would love it. Shoot, Amazon seems to know me that well, right!?</p>,<p>And I’m not talking about how we feel as parents when loving relatives buy more 48-piece toys for our children. There’s already stuff all over their floors (read: they already have more things than they are able to care for.)</p>,<p>But gift giving is FUN! And I’m a gifts person (from a Love Language perspective), so I love receiving gifts too.</p>,<p>But as a parent of six beautiful people under 13, the time to linger, browse, shop, ponder, consider, bargain-hunt, etc. just doesn’t exist. Neither does the budget for that matter.</p>,<p>So year after year, I’m frustrated...that we get too much stuff, or I don’t get the right stuff, or we did a gift exchange and I only gave one gift and received one gift...boy that’s a lot of pressure!! ONE GIFT, that’s it man. You’re whole Christmas experience is wrapped up in this single person’s ability to pick the right gift, the (as the advertisements go) “perfect gift.”</p>,<p>Before my mind wanders to the real Perfect Gift and I Jesus juke this moment, what do I really think?</p>,<p>Honestly, I’m having one of those moments where you base your expectations on what you experienced as children and not on the Story.</p>,<p>I remember (mostly by the scanned slides I have) of happy Christmases. Even as missionaries in Costa Rica, where I spent my first eleven Christmases. Presents from grandparents, home-built treasures from my Dad’s workshop, and special “big” toys/bikes/train sets.</p>,<p>So what trips me up about the gifts culture? (And I’m not really addressing the commercialization. That’s it’s own manure performance.)</p>,<p>I mean, my thought process for “why we do gifts” in the first place usually goes:</p>,<p>God modeled this for us by giving us Jesus as a gift - the gift of salvation. We are to love each other, and gifts are a tangible way to demonstrate this. Oh, the wise men, of course, they brought gifts...but those were for the baby Jesus.</p>,<p>But what really trips me up? No time, no money to do it like I’d like to? That’s where I’ll leave it for today.</p>,<p>So why do we give each other gifts?</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6c8a00f8-b4ef-4464-9156-c7224a28e274.jpg">,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTNm603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qey0YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fS2FFYUy2aOkPvw2JT5vy1iUrSaPuwSZrB6WC9S8xS0JKxqfiJhBgVipbrpiVRCSP3EJ5P0IELtD2_qf1OdZBQ-vHwWTDaNiL5j9meX0zCVKlACAO6CTMTaQQVYMYxQ8ENaQ33rLnCJKHmMj6E0NNTnmvvHOggG6Wh9v4oHYQc3Nf7a07mKFu6-27q7lSt7kdAYivV-CjX8UTG28teISvtvAFpHQGGLTQeIZndpUX0mxivh2mfpYivucT8uullLbFOnKZFmc-pRVE5BatPiuiSrfbdJZuFMCqo7IDQVIvJAO-PwA4o4MA5u70-oKXQKZI8kxvQ0NWA2XqedEPXewrMurrd6g84apdI" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-2/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84128d95-612e-41b6-a11b-6a30a24e5a8b</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 18:06:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 1]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 1</h1>,<p>Christmases over the last 20 years have seldom been meaningful.</p>,<p>At times sentimental. At times bluer than blue. At times just busy.</p>,<p>With only glimpses of wonder.</p>,<p>I mean, it is a pretty remarkable story after all. Why would God choose such a risky strategy? Sending HOPE in the most vulnerable, needy package. A baby. A toddler. A child. A teenager. An adolescent.</p>,<p>And the whole story of “the night” was pretty...remarkable. Not to mention the setup. And the silence of 4,800 months leading up to it.</p>,<p>Beyond all that, the sheer significance of who this Baby becomes for the whole world...it’s easy to see why the entire planet has embraced some form of celebrating it.</p>,<p>Songs. Parties. Traditions. Rituals.</p>,<p>But it’s become suffocated.</p>,<p>I was just watching a baking show where the judges were deciding which contestant had created the most decadent dessert. They described what Christmas is all about...family, food, fun.</p>,<p>Ah, “the holidays.” So far, far removed from “the holy days.”</p>,<p>So this is simply my journey to wrestle with all the clutter, do find the real meaning, the real core of Christmas. And then to build new traditions and celebrations around that core. Ones that preserve and highlight the core. Ones that our family of eight can integrate. And pass on.</p>,<p>As I write that, I sound pretentious. “Let me reject all of those traditions that Christians have created for centuries, and make my own, more enlightened ones.”</p>,<p>That’s not what I’m saying. I’m recognizing that I have things personally that don’t fit. I have expectations, hang ups, cultures, notions, dreams, etc.</p>,<p>It may be that part of my research will find wonderful traditions that do exactly what I’m hoping, that I can adopt.</p>,<p>But first, deconstruct. Then rebuild. Follow my journey if you’d like.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiLRVlpTBjfa7jCJA5ddgBNCKE3cLd2aVHZaMSH-HXcrErc4fn7P77kydhLW1HHb5Oh9iDdVwV-bqCKNdgibtB2dDta71KwErRibie9IiEmh6LhuOxK1MHIP4ekEPbhA2_Or2u9UDyll73cfJaNtK9L_mO352aRMlQmEMKKbMQuRRlABFhwzlNyQ1nDPmitMEmouk0MIAz0WhfbOgQ6yVRoa74_SQSjAfb69FGSOsqObr7bpT_X6dgIktlJPD_I-mcl4ezkoZKWdNyCtI8CwhdYjpIu7rIx-UuP1OO-zEsk1l4Rff3p5R6yTZFlZFUtqUVTNweqTIrpkq31_ySYWRgWVHxDaOp4N8P4I7IACjpyz2-sDWgq9IskzhQENfQOYr5dJN_aDp8Cs679b_QI4T5dH" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">66771619-be19-4be4-9ee0-862bfdb988c3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>