<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title><![CDATA[Reconstructing Christmas]]></title>
        <description><![CDATA[Reconstructing Christmas]]></description>
        <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/</link>
        <generator>The Grid</generator>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 17:29:51 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="http://reconstructingchristmas.com/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
        <pubDate>Wed, 05 Dec 2018 17:29:50 GMT</pubDate>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 4]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 4</h1>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/88d91840-4592-4834-985f-184cb9278964.jpg">,<p>There’s no other element of Christmas more quintessential than its MUSIC.</p>,<p>And this Amy Grant album is it for me. Always has been. Now it came out at the same time my family moved from Costa Rica to the scary world of the States. We crash landed in New Jersey for six terrible months, before gliding into a great 14 year season in San Antonio, Texas.</p>,<p>And this music was the soundtrack.</p>,<p>Ah a soundtrack for a season. Like a movie, the music of Christmas unifies and divides us. Well, that’s probably only true if you’re a worship leader. Then you hear ALL people’s expectations as they thrust upon you the songs you must include to avoid ruining their Christmas.</p>,<p>I hate that pressure.</p>,<p>But it’s undeniable. The season has a soundtrack.</p>,<p>There’s a lot of good music.</p>,<p>And there’s a lot of music.</p>,<p>In fact, though I’m listening to the aforementioned Christmas album as I type this in MOD Pizza, I’m being much more guarded this year about what I listen to. Because I feel like I’ve missed so much of what we are to celebrate, that I want to avoid being swept into it.</p>,<p>I’m not one to censor things, but I’m just trying to capture the HOLY essence, and that means blocking everything else out.</p>,<p>The idea of fuzzy antlers on Rudolph’s head, snowball fights, pumpkin pie shared by family, a star atop the Christmas tree, Santa’s sleigh, all the lore…I just need it to stop for a bit so I can focus!</p>,<p>So for this year, I’m trying to be vigilant. And I want to listen to the songs through a biblical narrative. Where is the story of Jesus? Where is the Anticipation of His arrival, not of Christmas morning!</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNkU9PwzAMxe_9FFGRaCttKX_EhbY7TOLAZRfghBDKEmdLtyZV7FZMiO-OOzqJWxz_8uz3Uhs3Cmea1G6XMQRKV3XJV6ukRh1dT6vcDl6TCz43C4ELZgvxnQgxqiharm2LohFG7oCejtCBJ1yfXtVuozrIsXi_-aiYdlbk_5n16dnkLFWICDREPzGzkI6gCGaOFSpuSGe458wfJjFqLrM9UY-PZamD96BJWqVhG8JBeqAS_OfbS4nmIFu8-rLb7tjcXo8Qka004728yyYx3l72KvKkTTAgnUeItAYbIuSzu6JKfnIT9DDtsxDZXy4Zny7zli3ynKwoqrqcU0uSegpWHxXiOVsdunM2qTCK1HIfwTbpZID3j8AOkOLAOfud3keH1CmU_GbG_dD1AYmlHi4f9AvE-ZOH" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-4/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">7f7e6aec-60a8-4c04-a337-77ee05f8e84a</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 19:05:36 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 3]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 3</h1>,<p>Christmas Morning!</p>,<p>Sure, it was staged…in classic Dad format - timer on the camera.</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/068cb7a3-6318-4eb6-8543-3e488628f49e.jpg">,<p>I think that the way we “do” Christmas Morning is…off.</p>,<blockquote>Hurry now, wake up your eyes. Time for little ones to see, Daddy&rsquo;s got a big surprise hiding underneath the Christmas tree.</blockquote>,<p>If we have to “reinterpret” a moment or a tradition so that it has meaning, is that something we want to keep?</p>,<p>So the kids get up first because, well duh. Then they attack their stockings, which for our family is a piece of fruit, some small gifts, maybe some gum.</p>,<p>Then the asking begins. “Can we open presents yet?!?”</p>,<p>I remember that. I want to open presents too! But wait…first we have to read the Christmas story so that our paper-tearing frenzy has some MEANING.</p>,<p>Ew.</p>,<p>I don’t think I’m just dealing with “life with small children.” As parents, we are the leaders here. We can create whatever culture we feel is best. Doesn’t matter if the culture around us is different.</p>,<p>The tradition/rhythm/expectation/culture we create must be compelling, worship-inspiring, family-strengthening.</p>,<p>But first, why the feasting - food and gifts. Why is that what is expected? Because Jesus’ gift is so lavish that we have to respond in kind?</p>,<p>I feel like I’m honestly doing a pretty terrible job of deconstruction. But it’s only day three.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTxm603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qey0YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fS2FFYUy2aOkPvw2JT5vy1iUrSaPuwSZrB6WC9S8xS0JKxqfiJhBgVipbrpiVRCSP3EJ5P0IELtD2_qf1OdZBQ-vHwWTDaNiL5j9meX0zCVKlACAO6CTMTaQQVYMYxQ8ENaQ33rLnCJKHmMj6E0NNTnmvvHOggG6Wh9v4oHYQc3Nf7a07mKFu6-27q7lSt7kdAYivVuJaP8UTG28teISvtvAFpHQGGLTQeIZndpUX0mxivh2mfpYivucT8uullLbFOnKZFmc-pRVE5BatPiuiSrfbdJZuFMCqo7IDQVIvJAO-PwA4o4MA5u70-oKXQKZI8kxvQ0NWA2XqedEPXewrMurrd6g84hZdJ" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-3/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">2b7593f9-420b-4c35-a9ed-b18c70808191</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 18:11:50 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 2]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 2</h1>,<h2>Wish Lists.</h2>,<p>We do this you know. We make and receive wish lists. For gifts.</p>,<p>I can’t help but wish that I’d know people well enough to not have to ask for their wish list. And I get it. Decades of jokes come from re-gifting things and there’s a whole demographic of people that seems to have a disproportionately low success rate in finding gifts that “stick.”</p>,<p>What if I didn’t buy anything for anybody that I didn’t know so well, I could just pick something because he/she would love it. Shoot, Amazon seems to know me that well, right!?</p>,<p>And I’m not talking about how we feel as parents when loving relatives buy more 48-piece toys for our children. There’s already stuff all over their floors (read: they already have more things than they are able to care for.)</p>,<p>But gift giving is FUN! And I’m a gifts person (from a Love Language perspective), so I love receiving gifts too.</p>,<p>But as a parent of six beautiful people under 13, the time to linger, browse, shop, ponder, consider, bargain-hunt, etc. just doesn’t exist. Neither does the budget for that matter.</p>,<p>So year after year, I’m frustrated...that we get too much stuff, or I don’t get the right stuff, or we did a gift exchange and I only gave one gift and received one gift...boy that’s a lot of pressure!! ONE GIFT, that’s it man. You’re whole Christmas experience is wrapped up in this single person’s ability to pick the right gift, the (as the advertisements go) “perfect gift.”</p>,<p>Before my mind wanders to the real Perfect Gift and I Jesus juke this moment, what do I really think?</p>,<p>Honestly, I’m having one of those moments where you base your expectations on what you experienced as children and not on the Story.</p>,<p>I remember (mostly by the scanned slides I have) of happy Christmases. Even as missionaries in Costa Rica, where I spent my first eleven Christmases. Presents from grandparents, home-built treasures from my Dad’s workshop, and special “big” toys/bikes/train sets.</p>,<p>So what trips me up about the gifts culture? (And I’m not really addressing the commercialization. That’s it’s own manure performance.)</p>,<p>I mean, my thought process for “why we do gifts” in the first place usually goes:</p>,<p>God modeled this for us by giving us Jesus as a gift - the gift of salvation. We are to love each other, and gifts are a tangible way to demonstrate this. Oh, the wise men, of course, they brought gifts...but those were for the baby Jesus.</p>,<p>But what really trips me up? No time, no money to do it like I’d like to? That’s where I’ll leave it for today.</p>,<p>So why do we give each other gifts?</p>,<img src="https://the-grid-user-content.s3-us-west-2.amazonaws.com/6c8a00f8-b4ef-4464-9156-c7224a28e274.jpg">,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiHRVlpTNm603WESBy67ACeEUJq4W7o1qey0YkL8O-7WSdzi-Pk9v-fS2FFYUy2aOkPvw2JT5vy1iUrSaPuwSZrB6WC9S8xS0JKxqfiJhBgVipbrpiVRCSP3EJ5P0IELtD2_qf1OdZBQ-vHwWTDaNiL5j9meX0zCVKlACAO6CTMTaQQVYMYxQ8ENaQ33rLnCJKHmMj6E0NNTnmvvHOggG6Wh9v4oHYQc3Nf7a07mKFu6-27q7lSt7kdAYivV-CjX8UTG28teISvtvAFpHQGGLTQeIZndpUX0mxivh2mfpYivucT8uullLbFOnKZFmc-pRVE5BatPiuiSrfbdJZuFMCqo7IDQVIvJAO-PwA4o4MA5u70-oKXQKZI8kxvQ0NWA2XqedEPXewrMurrd6g84apdI" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-2/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">84128d95-612e-41b6-a11b-6a30a24e5a8b</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Dec 2018 18:06:13 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title><![CDATA[December 1]]></title>
            <description><![CDATA[<h1>December 1</h1>,<p>Christmases over the last 20 years have seldom been meaningful.</p>,<p>At times sentimental. At times bluer than blue. At times just busy.</p>,<p>With only glimpses of wonder.</p>,<p>I mean, it is a pretty remarkable story after all. Why would God choose such a risky strategy? Sending HOPE in the most vulnerable, needy package. A baby. A toddler. A child. A teenager. An adolescent.</p>,<p>And the whole story of “the night” was pretty...remarkable. Not to mention the setup. And the silence of 4,800 months leading up to it.</p>,<p>Beyond all that, the sheer significance of who this Baby becomes for the whole world...it’s easy to see why the entire planet has embraced some form of celebrating it.</p>,<p>Songs. Parties. Traditions. Rituals.</p>,<p>But it’s become suffocated.</p>,<p>I was just watching a baking show where the judges were deciding which contestant had created the most decadent dessert. They described what Christmas is all about...family, food, fun.</p>,<p>Ah, “the holidays.” So far, far removed from “the holy days.”</p>,<p>So this is simply my journey to wrestle with all the clutter, do find the real meaning, the real core of Christmas. And then to build new traditions and celebrations around that core. Ones that preserve and highlight the core. Ones that our family of eight can integrate. And pass on.</p>,<p>As I write that, I sound pretentious. “Let me reject all of those traditions that Christians have created for centuries, and make my own, more enlightened ones.”</p>,<p>That’s not what I’m saying. I’m recognizing that I have things personally that don’t fit. I have expectations, hang ups, cultures, notions, dreams, etc.</p>,<p>It may be that part of my research will find wonderful traditions that do exactly what I’m hoping, that I can adopt.</p>,<p>But first, deconstruct. Then rebuild. Follow my journey if you’d like.</p>,<iframe src="https://the-grid.github.io/ed-userhtml/?g=eJxNUcFOwzAMvfcroiLRVlpTBjfa7jCJA5ddgBNCKE3cLd2aVHZaMSH-HXcrErc4fn7P77kydhLW1HHb5Oh9iDdVwV-bqCKNdgibtB2dDta71KwErRibie9IiEmh6LhuOxK1MHIP4ekEPbhA2_Or2u9UDyll73cfJaNtK9L_mO352aRMlQmEMKKbMQuRRlABFhwzlNyQ1nDPmitMEmouk0MIAz0WhfbOgQ6yVRoa74_SQSjAfb69FGSOsqObr7bpT_X6dgIktlJPD_I-mcl4ezkoZKWdNyCtI8CwhdYjpIu7rIx-UuP1OO-zEsk1l4Rff3p5R6yTZFlZFUtqUVTNweqTIrpkq31_ySYWRgWVHxDaOp4N8P4I7IACjpyz2-sDWgq9IskzhQENfQOYr5dJN_aDp8Cs679b_QI4T5dH" height="244"></iframe>]]></description>
            <link>http://reconstructingchristmas.com/december-1/index.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">66771619-be19-4be4-9ee0-862bfdb988c3</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Dec 2018 16:29:24 GMT</pubDate>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>